American Painting Section of the Mounted Photograph Collection
Yale University Arts Library
- S (Box 113)
  - Miscellaneous Artists: Sm., 14 (Box 114)
    - Smith, Alice R.H., 1876-1958., 1 (Box 114)
    - Smith, Allen, 19th c., 1 (Box 114)
    - Smith, David,1906-?., 1 (Box 114)
    - Smith, F. Hopkinson, 1838-1915., 1 (Box 114)
    - Smith, Frank V., 20th c., 2 (Box 114)
    - Smith, Jessie Wilcox, 1863-1935., 2 (Box 114)
    - Smith, Leon Polk, 1906-?., 2 (Box 114)
    - Smith, Richard, 1931-., 1 (Box 114)
    - Smith, Xanthus, 1839-1929., 1 (Box 114)
    - Smithson, Robert, 1938-1973., 1 (Box 114)
  - Miscellaneous Artists: So-Sp., 12 (Box 114)
    - Solman, Joseph, 20th c., 1 (Box 114)
    - Solomon, Hyde, 1911-?., 2 (Box 114)
    - Sonnier, Keith, 1941-., 1 (Box 114)
    - Sonntag, William L., 1822-1900., 2 (Box 114)
    - Specer, Lilly Martin, 19th c., 1 (Box 114)
    - Spero, Nancy, 20th c., 3 (Box 114)
    - Spruce, Everett Franklin, 1907-?., 2 (Box 114)
  - Miscellaneous Artists: Sta-Ste., 18 (Box 115)
    - Stadler, Albert, 20th c., 1 (Box 115)
    - Stanley, John Mix, 1814-1872., 3 (Box 115)
    - Starkweather, William, 1879-?., 2 (Box 115)
    - Stearns, Junius Brutus, 1810-1885., 2 (Box 115)
    - Steinberg, Saul, 1914-?., 1 (Box 115)
    - Steiner, Michael, 20th c., 1 (Box 115)
    - Steir, Pat, 20th c., 3 (Box 115)
    - Stevens, John, 19th c., 2 (Box 115)
    - Steward, Joseph, 1752-1822., 1 (Box 115)
    - Stewart, Jack, 20th c., 2 (Box 115)
  - Miscellaneous Artists: Sto-Sy., 20 (Box 115)
    - Stock, Joseph Whiting, 1815-1855., 1 (Box 115)
    - Stoddard, Alice Kent, 1884-1976., 1 (Box 115)
    - Stoll, Rolf, 20th c., 1 (Box 115)
    - Stone, William Oliver, 1830-1875., 1 (Box 115)
    - Storrs, John, 1887-?., 1 (Box 115)
    - Stouter, D.G., 19th c., 1 (Box 115)
    - Stovall, Queena, 1888-?., 1 (Box 115)
    - Street, Robert, 1796-1865., 1 (Box 115)
    - Strycker, Jacobus Gerritsen, 1617-1687., 1 (Box 115)
    - Stuart, James R., 1834-1915., 1 (Box 115)
    - Sugarman, George, 1912-., 1 (Box 115)
    - Sully, Lawrence, 1769-1804., 1 (Box 115)
    - Sultan, Donald, 1951-., 2 (Box 115)
    - Surls, James, 1943-., 1 (Box 115)
    - Suydam, James Augustus, 1817-1865., 1 (Box 115)
    - Swain, Robert, 1940-., 3 (Box 115)
    - Symons, Gardner, 1861-?., 1 (Box 115)
  - Individual Artists (Box 115)
    - Salle, David, 1952-., 5 (Box 115)
    - Salmon, Robert W., 1775-c. 1845., 6 (Box 115)
    - Sample, Paul, 1896-1974., 18 (Box 115)
    - Sargent, Henry, 1770-1845., 4 (Box 115)
    - Sargent, John Singer, 1856-1925., total of 211 photographs. (Box 115–118)
      - Drawings, 17 (Box 116)
      - Location Unknown, 38 (Box 116)
      - Private Collection, 9 (Box 116)
      - Miscellaneous Cities: A-K, 26 (Box 117)
      - Miscellaneous Cities: L-Z, 20 (Box 117)
      - Boston (Box 117)
        - Individual Repositories, Boston: Isabella Stewart Gardner Museum, 4 (Box 117)
        - Individual Repositories, Boston: Museum of Fine Arts, 17 (Box 117)
        - Individual Repositories, Boston: Boston Public Library, 17 (Box 118)
      - London, 14 (Box 118)
      - New York, 24 (Box 118)
        - Individual Repositories, New York: Brooklyn Museum, 16 (Box 118)
      - Washington D.C., 9 (Box 118)
    - Saul, Peter, 1934-., 6 (Box 119)
    - Savage, Edward, 1761-1817., 8 (Box 119)
    - Savage, Eugene Francis, 1883-1966., 6 (Box 119)
    - Schamberg, Morton Livingston, 1881-1918., 3 (Box 119)
    - Schapiro, Miriam, 1923-., 8 (Box 119)
    - Schwabacher, Ethel, 1903-1984., 15 (Box 119)
    - Schnakenberg, Henry, 1892-1970., 3 (Box 119)
    - Schreiber, Georges, act. 1906-., 3 (Box 119)
    - Shahn, Ben, 1898-1969., total of 76 photographs. (Box 119–120)
      - Location Unknown, 15 (Box 120)
      - Private Collection, 14 (Box 120)
      - Miscellaneous Cities: A-Z, 15 (Box 120)
      - New York, 16 (Box 120)
    - Sharples, James, 1751-1811., 8 (Box 120)
    - Sharrer, Honore, 1920-., 5 (Box 121)
    - Shaw, Charles, 1892-1974., 6 (Box 121)
    - Shaw, Joshua, 1776-1860., 5 (Box 121)
    - Sheeler, Charles, 1883-1965., Total of 44 photographs. (Box 121)
      - Drawings, 3 (Box 121)
      - Location Unknown, 9 (Box 121)
      - Private Collection, 6 (Box 121)
      - Miscellaneous Cities: A-Z, 10 (Box 121)
      - New York, 11 (Box 121)
      - Philadelphia, 5 (Box 121)
    - Sheets, Millard, 1907-1989., 4 (Box 122)
    - Shinn, Everett, 1873-1953., 4 (Box 122)
    - Siporin, Mitchell, 1910-., 5 (Box 122)
    - Sloan, John, 1871-1951., Total of 42 photographs. (Box 122)
      - Location Unknown, 9 (Box 122)
      - Private Collection, 3 (Box 122)
      - Miscellaneous Cities: A-Z, 24 (Box 122)
      - Washington D.C., 6 (Box 122)
    - Smibert, John, 1688-1751., Total of 56 photographs. (Box 122–123)
      - Location Unknown, 1 (Box 123)
      - Private Collection, 1 (Box 123)
      - Miscellaneous Cities: A-Z, 21 (Box 123)
      - Boston, 15 (Box 123)
      - New Haven, 11 (Box 123)
      - New York, 7 (Box 123)
    - Smith, Thomas, act. 1680-1693., 5 (Box 124)
    - Sommer, William, 1867-1949., 9 (Box 124)
    - Soyer, Raphael, 1899-., 11 (Box 124)
    - Speicher, Eugene, 1883-1962., Total of 25 photographs. (Box 124)
      - Location Unknown, 11 (Box 124)
      - Miscellaneous Cities: A-Z, 14 (Box 124)
    - Spencer, Niles, 1893-1952., 6 (Box 124)
    - Spencer, Robert, 1879-1931., 7 (Box 125)
    - Stamos, Theodorus, 1922-., 8 (Box 125)
    - Steinberg, Saul, 1914-., 9 (Box 125)
    - Stella, Frank, 1936-., 42 (Box 125)
    - Stella, Joseph, 1877-1946., Total of 20 photographs. (Box 125–126)
      - Location Unknown, 2 (Box 126)
      - New Haven, 7 (Box 126)
      - New York, 2 (Box 126)
      - Newark, 9 (Box 126)
    - Sterne, Hedda, 1916-., 6 (Box 126)
    - Sterne, Maurice, 1877-1957., total of 18 photographs. (Box 126–127)
      - Drawings, 4 (Box 127)
      - Paintings, 13 (Box 127)
    - Sterner, Albert, 1863-1946., 3 (Box 127)
    - Stettheimer, Florine, 1871-1944., 5 (Box 127)
    - Still, Clyfford, 1904-1980., 27 (Box 127)
    - Stock, Joseph Whiting, 1815-1855., 3 (Box 127)
    - Stuart, Gilbert, 1755-1828., Total of 128 photographs. (Box 127–129)
      - Location Unknown, 7 (Box 128)
      - Location Unknown, cont., 23 (Box 128)
      - Private Collection, 12 (Box 128)
      - Miscellaneous Cities: A-Z, 21 (Box 128)
      - Boston, 10 (Box 129)
      - New Haven, 9 (Box 129)
      - New York, 18 (Box 129)
      - Philadelphia, 10 (Box 129)
      - Washington D.C., 18 (Box 129)
    - Stuempfig, Walter, 1914-., 5 (Box 130)
    - Sully, Thomas, 1783-1872., Total of 45 photographs. (Box 130)
      - Location Unknown, 9 (Box 130)
      - Miscellaneous Cities: A-C, 12 (Box 130)
      - Miscellaneous Cities: D-P, 17 (Box 130)
      - Miscellaneous Cities: Q-Z, 7 (Box 130)
- T (Box 130)
  Includes a folder of miscellaneous clippings for various "T" artists.
  - Miscellaneous Artists: Ta-Te., 22 (Box 131)
    - Tabachnik, Anne, 1933-., 1 (Box 131)
    - Tait, Agnes, 1897-1981., 1 (Box 131)
    - Tait, Arthur Fitzwilliam, 1819-1905., 1 (Box 131)
    - Tanning, Dorothea, 20th c., 2 (Box 131)
    - Tansey, Mark, 1949-., 3 (Box 131)
    - Taubes, Frederick, 1900-?., 2 (Box 131)
    - Taylor, Edwin Cassius, 1874-1935., 2 (Box 131)
    - Taylor, Richard, 1902-?., 2 (Box 131)
    - Tenney, U.D., 19th c., 1 (Box 131)
    - Terry, Eliphalet, 1826-1896., 1 (Box 131)
  - Miscellaneous Artists: Th., 15 (Box 131)
    - Thieme, Anthony, 1888-?., 1 (Box 131)
    - Thompson, A.F., 19th c., 2 (Box 131)
    - Thompson, George Albert, 1868-1938., 1 (Box 131)
    - Thompson, Jerome B., 1814-1886., 3 (Box 131)
    - Thompson, Robert, 20th c., 3 (Box 131)
    - Thon, William, 1906-?., 3 (Box 131)
    - Thurber, James, 1894-?., 2 (Box 131)
  - Miscellaneous Artists: Ti-Tw., Total of 24 photographs. (Box 131)
    - Tilles, J.A., 19th c., 1 (Box 131)
    - Tillim, Sidney, 1925-?., 1 (Box 131)
    - Tirrell, George, 19th c., 1 (Box 131)
    - Tittle, Walter, 1883-?., 1 (Box 131)
    - Tofel, Jennings, 1891-1959., 1 (Box 131)
    - Tooker, George, 1921-?., 3 (Box 131)
    - Traylor, Bill, 1854-1947., 2 (Box 131)
    - Treasure, Frank H., 19th c., 1 (Box 131)
    - Trotter, N.H., 1827-1898., 1 (Box 131)
    - Trova, Ernest, 1927-., 2 (Box 131)
    - Troye, Edward, 1808-1874., 3 (Box 131)
    - True, David, 1942-., 1 (Box 131)
    - Tryon, Dwight William, 1849-1925., 1 (Box 131)
    - Turner, Helen Maria, 1858-1958., 3 (Box 131)
    - Tuttle, Richard, 1941-., 1 (Box 131)
    - Twibill, George Jr., 1806-1836., 1 (Box 131)
  - Individual Artists (Box 132)
    - Tack, Augustus Vincent, 1870-1949., 7 (Box 132)
    - Tait, Arthur Fitzwilliam, 1819- 1905., 10 (Box 132)
    - Tanner, Henry Ossawa, 1899-1937, 6 (Box 132)
    - Tarbell, Edmund Charles, 1862-1938., 9 (Box 132)
    - Thayer, Abbott H., 1849-1921., 14 (Box 132)
    - Theus, Jeremiah, c.1719-1774., 7 (Box 132)
    - Thiebaud, Wayne, 1920-., 11 (Box 133)
    - Thomas, Byron, 1902-., 4 (Box 133)
    - Thompson, Alfred, ?-1895., 4 (Box 133)
    - Tobey, Mark, 1890-1976., 31 (Box 133)
    - Tomlin, Bradley Walker, 1899-1953., 7 (Box 133)
    - Trumbull, John, 1756-1843., 144 (Box 133–135)
      - Location Unknown, 10 (Box 134)
      - Private Collection, 7 (Box 134)
      - Miscellaneous Cities: A-D, 8 (Box 134)
      - Miscellaneous Cities: E-Z, 17 (Box 134)
      - Boston, 20 (Box 134)
      - New Haven, 20 (Box 135)
      - New Haven, cont., 62 (Box 135)
    - Tryon, Dwight W., 1849-1925., 3 (Box 136)
    - Tucker, Allen, 1866-1939., 6 (Box 136)
    - Tucker, Allen, 1866-1939, cont., 10 (Box 136)
    - Twachtman, John Henry, 1853-1902., 35 (Box 136)
    - Twombly, Cy, 1928-., 21 (Box 136)
    - Tworkov, Jack, 1900-1982., 5 (Box 136)
- U (Box 137)
  Includes a folder of miscellaneous clippings for the "U" artists.
  - Individual Artists (Box 137)
    - Ufer, Walter, 1876-1936., 3 (Box 137)
    - Ulrich, Charles Frederic, 1858-1908., 1 (Box 137)
    - Underwood, Leon, 1890-1975., 2 (Box 137)
- V (Box 137)
  Includes a folder of miscellaneous clippings for various "V" artists.
  - Miscellaneous Artists: Va-Vi., 15 (Box 137)
    - Vago, Sandor, 20th c., 1 (Box 137)
    - Valerio, James, 1938-., 2 (Box 137)
    - Van Boskerck, 1855-1932., 1 (Box 137)
    - Van Campen, Susan Headley, 1951-., 1 (Box 137)
    - Van Dalen, Anton, 20th c., 1 (Box 137)
    - Vanderlyn, Peter, 1687-1788., 2 (Box 137)
    - Van Everen, Jay, 1775-1847., 1 (Box 137)
    - Van Ness, Beatrice Whitney, 1888-1981., 1 (Box 137)
    - Varga, Margit, 20th c., 2 (Box 137)
    - Vicente, Esteban, 1904-?., 2 (Box 137)
    - Vidar, Frede, 20th c., 1 (Box 137)
  - Miscellaneous Artists: Vo-Vy., 6 (Box 137)
    - Vonnoh, Robert, 1858-1933., 3 (Box 137)
    - Von Wiegand, Charmion, 20th c., 1 (Box 137)
    - Voss, F.B., 19th c., 1 (Box 137)
    - Vytlacil, Vaclav, 1893-?., 1 (Box 137)
  - Individual Artists (Box 138)
    - Vanderlyn, John, 1775-1852., 24 (Box 138)
      - Location Unknown, 2 (Box 138)
      - Miscellaneous Cities: A-L, 10 (Box 138)
      - Miscellaneous Cities: M-Z, 12 (Box 138)
    - Vedder, Elihu, 1836-1923., 6 (Box 138)
    - Vedder, Elihu, 1836-1923, cont., 13 (Box 138)
    - Volk, Douglas, 1856-after 1925., 4 (Box 138)
- W (Box 139)
  Includes a folder of miscellaneous clippings for various "W" artists.
  - Miscellaneous Artists: Wa-We., 24 (Box 139)
    - Wachs, Gretchen, 20th c., 1 (Box 139)
    - Wagner, Henry M..,19th c., 1 (Box 139)
    - Wald, Sylvia, 20th c., 1 (Box 139)
    - Walker, Henry Oliver, 1843-?., 1 (Box 139)
    - Walker, William Aiken, 1838-1921., 3 (Box 139)
    - Walkowitz, Abraham, 1878-1965., 1 (Box 139)
    - Walter, Martha, 1875-1976., 2 (Box 139)
    - Walton, Henry, 1804-1865., 1 (Box 139)
    - Waters, E.A., 19th c., 1 (Box 139)
    - Waterson, J.R., act. 1846-1859., 1 (Box 139)
    - Waud, Alfred R., 1828-1891., 1 (Box 139)
    - Weber, Idelle, 20th c., 3 (Box 139)
    - Weiner, Lawrence, 1942-., 1 (Box 139)
    - Weir, Irene, 20th c., 1 (Box 139)
    - Wenderoth, August, 1825-?., 1 (Box 139)
    - Westermann, H.C., 1922-1981., 1 (Box 139)
    - Wetherby, Isaac Augustus, 1819-1904., 1 (Box 139)
    - Weyden, Harry van der, 1868-?., 2 (Box 139)
  - Miscellaneous Artists: Wh-Wi., 20 (Box 139)
    - Whitaker, Frederic, 20th c., 1 (Box 139)
    - Whitney, L., 19th c?., 1 (Box 139)
    - Wiggins, Guy, 19th c?., 1 (Box 139)
    - Wilde, John, 1912-?., 1 (Box 139)
    - Wiley, William Thomas, 1937-?., 2 (Box 139)
    - Williams, Henry, 19th c?., 1 (Box 139)
    - Williams, William, ?-1790., 3 (Box 139)
    - Williams, William Jr., 1759-1823., 1 (Box 139)
    - Willis, Thorton, 20th c., 1 (Box 139)
    - Wilson, Jane, 20th c., 1 (Box 139)
    - Wilson, Mary Ann, act. 1810-1825., 1 (Box 139)
    - Wilson, Sol, 1894-?., 2 (Box 139)
    - Wimar, Carl, 1826-1862., 2 (Box 139)
    - Winter, C, 19th c., 1 (Box 139)
    - Witkin, Jerome, 20th c., 1 (Box 139)
  - Miscellaneous Artists: Wo-Wy., 17 (Box 139)
    - Woelffer, Emerson, 1914-?., 1 (Box 139)
    - Woffard, Philip, 20th c., 2 (Box 139)
    - Wojnarowicz, David, 20th c., 1 (Box 139)
    - Wolff, Robert J., 1905-?., 1 (Box 139)
    - Wood, Christopher, 1901-1930., 1 (Box 139)
    - Woodside, John A., act. 1815-1850., 1 (Box 139)
    - Wores, Theodore, 1860-1934., 1 (Box 139)
    - Wornum, Mirium, 1898-?., 1 (Box 139)
    - Wright, Stanton MacDonald, 1880-?., 1 (Box 139)
    - Wright, George Frederick, 19th c., 1 (Box 139)
    - Wright, J.H., 19th c., 1 (Box 139)
    - Wujcik, Theo, 1946-., 1 (Box 139)
    - Wunderman, Jan, 20th c., 1 (Box 139)
    - Wyeth, Henriette, 1907-?., 2 (Box 139)
    - Wylie, Theophilus Adam, 19th c?., 1 (Box 139)
  - Individual Artists (Box 140)
    - Waldo, Samuel Lovett, 1783-1861., 12 (Box 140)
    - Walker, Horatio, 1858-1938., 3 (Box 140)
    - Warhol, Andy, 1930-1987., Total of 38 photographs. (Box 140)
    - Walkowitz, Abraham, 1880-1965., 3 (Box 141)
    - Warshawsky, Abel George, 1883-1962., 4 (Box 141)
    - Watkins, Franklin C., 1894-1972., 9 (Box 141)
    - Watrous, Harry William, 1857-1940., 3 (Box 141)
    - Watson, John, 1685-1768., 4 (Box 141)
    - Waugh, Frederick J., 1861-1940., 7 (Box 141)
    - Weber, Max, 1881-1961., Total of 36 photographs. (Box 141–142)
      - Miscellaneous Cities: A-Z, 15 (Box 142)
      - New Haven, 5 (Box 142)
      - New York, 16 (Box 142)
    - Weir, John Ferguson, 1841-1926., total of 35 photographs. (Box 142–143)
      - Location Unknown, 2 (Box 143)
      - Private Collection, 1 (Box 143)
      - New Haven, 32 (Box 143)
    - Weir, Julian Alden, 1852-1919., 22 (Box 143)
    - Weir, Robert W., 1803-1889., 5 (Box 143)
    - Welliver, Neil, 1929-., 9 (Box 143)
    - Wesselmann, Tom, 1931-., 7 (Box 143)
    - West, Benjamin, 1738-1820., Total of 207 photographs. (Box 143–146)
      - Drawings, 10 (Box 144)
      - Location Unknown, 14 (Box 144)
      - Private Collection, 30 (Box 144)
      - Miscellaneous Cities: A-C, 15 (Box 145)
      - Miscellaneous Cities: D-M, 27 (Box 145)
      - Miscellaneous Cities: N-O, 20 (Box 145)
      - Miscellaneous Cities: P-Z, 19 (Box 145)
      - London, 27 (Box 146)
      - New Haven, 11 (Box 146)
      - New York, 11 (Box 146)
      - Philadelphia, 15 (Box 146)
      - Washington D.C., 8 (Box 146)
    - Whistler, James McNeil, 1834-1903., total of 133 photographs. (Box 146–148)
      - Location Unknown, 19 (Box 147)
      - Private Collection, 6 (Box 147)
      - Miscellaneous Cities: A-B, 7 (Box 147)
      - Miscellaneous Cities: C-K, 17 (Box 147)
      - Miscellaneous Cities: L-Z, 13 (Box 147)
      - Chicago, 10 (Box 148)
      - Glasgow, 6 (Box 148)
      - London, 15 (Box 148)
      - New York, 12 (Box 148)
      - Washington D.C., 28 (Box 148)
    - White, John, act. 1577-1593., 3 (Box 149)
    - Whittredge, Thomas Worthington (T.W.), 1820- 1910., 10 (Box 149)
    - Wilcox, Frank Nelson, 1887-1964., 7 (Box 149)
    - Wiles, Irving R., 1861-1948., 4 (Box 149)
    - Wimar, Charles Ferdinand, 1828-1862., 3 (Box 149)
    - Winter, Ezra Augustus, 1886-., 3 (Box 149)
    - Wollaston, John, act. 1734-1767., 14 (Box 149)
    - Wood, Grant, 1892-1942., Total of 29 photographs. (Box 149–150)
      - Location Unknown, 8 (Box 150)
      - Private Collection, 3 (Box 150)
      - Miscellaneous Cities: A-Z, 18 (Box 150)
    - Wood, Thomas Waterman, 1823-1903., 4 (Box 150)
    - Woodbury, Charles Herbert, 1864-1940., 3 (Box 150)
    - Woodville, Richard Caton, 1825-1855., 11 (Box 150)
    - Woodward, Robert Strong, 1885-1955., 4 (Box 150)
    - Wright, Joseph, 1756-1793., 5 (Box 150)
    - Wyant, Alexander H., 1836-1892., 18 (Box 151)
    - Wyeth, Andrew, 1917-., total of 36 photographs. (Box 151)
      - Location Unknown, 13 (Box 151)
      - Private Collection, 13 (Box 151)
      - Miscellaneous Cities: A-Z, 10 (Box 151)
    - Wyeth, Newell Convers (N.C.), 1882-1945., 7 (Box 151)
- X (Box 152)
  Includes a folder of miscellaneous clippings for various "X" artists.
  - Individual Artists (Box 152)
    - Xceron, Jean, 1890-1967., 6 (Box 152)
- Y (Box 152)
  Includes a folder of miscellaneous clippings for various "Y" artists.
  - Individual Artists (Box 152)
    - Young, James Harvey, 1830-1918., 1 (Box 152)
    - Young, Mahonri, 1877-1957., 1 (Box 152)
    - Youngerman, Jack, 1926-., 5 (Box 152)
    - Yrissary, Mario, 1933-., 4 (Box 152)
    - Yunkers, Adja, 1900-1983., 1 (Box 152)
- Z (Box 152)
  Includes a folder of miscellaneous clippings for various "Z" artists.
  - Individual Artists (Box 152)
    - Zapkus, Kestutis Edward, 1938-., 3 (Box 152)
    - Zerbe, Karl, 1903-1972., 4 (Box 152)
    - Zieman, Richard Claude, 1932-., 1 (Box 152)
    - Zingale, Santos, 1908-., 1 (Box 152)
    - Zogbaum, Rufus Fairchild, 1849-1925., 1 (Box 152)
    - Zorach, Marguerite, 1887-1968., 2 (Box 152)
    - Zorach, William, 1887-1966., 3 (Box 152)
    - Zox, Larry, 1936-., 1 (Box 152)
    - Zucker, Joe, 1941-., 1 (Box 152)